** Lily has always been one of those people who loves their birthday.
孩子们  你们阿姨Lily是一个 爱过生日的人
Loves it.
超爱的
It's my birthday!
今天是我生日!
So it's a good thing she married Marshall.
所以好在她嫁给了Marshall
It's still my birthday!
还是我生日哎!
Because he loves planning birthdays.
因为他爱策划生日
Feliz cumplea卤os,baby.
宝贝 生日快乐 (西班牙语)
The theme of this today's birthday breakfast in bed is...
今天的床上生日早餐主题是...
"Spanish Interlude"
"西班牙小曲儿"
and ...
还有..
How on Earth did we end up in the lyrical rolling hills of Northern Spain?
我们怎么到了西班牙北部 充满诗意的山脉来了?
Baby,tonight is going to be so much fun.
宝贝 今天晚上一定会非常有趣的
Just the five of us,black-tie dinner,
只有我们五个人 正装晚餐
and Ted is picking up your favorite cognac pumpkin cheesecake from Edgar's.
Ted会去Edgar's家去买你最爱的 干邑南瓜起司蛋糕
Okay,I am off to run your super secret birthday errand.
好了 我要去筹备 你的超级神秘生日派对事宜了
And I'm taking this guy with me
我要顺便把这个家伙带走
because I don't like the way he's looking at you.
我不喜欢他看你的眼神
A new camera! Oh,thank you,Marshall. I love it!
新相机! 谢谢你 Marshall 我喜欢
Well,little bonus: I took some naked pictures of myself before I wrapped it.
附赠惊喜:我包起来之前拍了几张裸照
Put a bow on it.
上面还打了个蝴蝶结
There wasn't a bow on it.
上面没有蝴蝶结啊
Wrong "it.
我不是说相机
" Thank you,honey. I'm going to get some great shots of our little group with this.
谢谢你宝贝 我要给我们几个人拍几张好照片
Now,kids,you've seen your Aunt Lily's photo albums:
孩子们 你们看过Lily阿姨的相册
leather bound,acid free paper,adorable handwritten captions.
皮质封面 防蚀纸 可爱的手写附注
And most importantly,the group shot.
最重要的 是大家的集体照
Cute photo,right,kids?
照片很可爱 对吧 孩子们
But what you don't see is what happened
但是你们没看到
ten seconds before this picture was taken.
拍照十秒钟前都发生了什么
10***
拍照十秒钟前
Okay,I want to get the perfect group shot.
我要拍一张完美的集体照
Marshall,sit between Barney and Robin.
Marshall 坐在Barney和Robin中间
- wait - Why?
- 等一下 - 为什么?
Oh,you know,uh,light,color,balance,aperture...
哦 你知道 光线 颜色 平衡 光圈...
You're just saying camera words.
你不过是在顺口胡诌摄影专业词汇
Wait - you don't want Barney and me
等一下 你不想在你的照片你
to look like a couple in this picture,do you?
我和Barney看起来是一对 是吧
Of course I don't! You two aren't going to last!
我当然不想 你们俩好不了几天了
I'm going for timeless here.
我照片可是要永久保存呢
How dare you?
你怎么敢这么说?
- That is so rude! - It's true.
- 太没礼貌了 - 虽然是实话
Totally true - we're running on fumes here,but still rude.
绝对实话 我们俩快散伙了 但是你这么说还是很没礼貌
We hated Lily's group shots.
我们痛恨Lily的集体照
Okay,maybe I get a little bossy,but I just want to remember those times.
好吧 我可能确实有点霸道 但是我只是想记住这些时刻
Like tonight. I can't imagine a better birthday than,
像今天晚上 我想不出比
than being here with just my four best friends.
只和我四个最好的朋友在一起 更好的生日聚会
And Ted's here now.
Ted也来了
Happy birthday! This is Amanda.
生日快乐!这是Amanda
And Amanda... yay.
还有Amanda...耶!
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=- Proudly Presents
-=伊甸园美剧 http://bbs.sfileydy.com=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业途径
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=- Sync: 卡灰
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=- 翻译: 加肥猫 鱼豆腐 校对: 葱家的小猫毛 时间轴:卡灰
how i met your mother  s05e18
老爸老妈浪漫史 第五季 第18集
Ted,you were supposed to bring a cheesecake,
Ted 我叫你去买蛋糕的
but instead you brought two grocery bags and a woman we've never seen before.
但是你却带回来两个购物袋 还有个我们从来没见过的女人
Hi. I'm Marshall. Welcome to our home. Start talking.
嗨 我是Marshall 欢迎来我们家 开始交代吧你
Amanda's going to make Lily a cake. She's a chef.
Amanda要给Lily做个蛋糕 她是个大厨
We met when I was at a restaurant last week and I sent some soup back.
我们上周在一间餐厅认识的 当时我要求退汤
Lucky,she's got such pretty hair I didn't mind eating a little bit of it.
谁知道她有这么漂亮的头发 那我吃点就吃点吧
They call me "The Shedder" at work.
我同事都叫我剪毛器
I'm so glad you're making my birthday cake!
你要给我做生日蛋糕我太高兴了
In honor of Lily's 32nd birthday,
为了纪念Lily的32岁生日
I've got a lot of great games planned,starting with...
我准备好了多好玩的游戏 首先开始的是..
"Lil-ial Pursuit.
"Lily的爱好"
" Okay,who's got number one?
好了 谁先来?
I do.
我
Of course you do. Okay,Amanda goes first.
当然是你 好了 Amanda先来
32 seconds on the clock to answer as many questions as possible.
计时32秒回答尽可能多问题
And... Go! Question one: What is Lily's favorite color?
准备...开始!问题一 Lily最喜欢的颜色是什么?
Well,she's wearing pink,so I'm going to say pink.
啊 她穿的是粉色 那我就猜粉色
Okay,that's Robin.
穿粉色的是Robin
Oh,uh...
哦 啊...
Her... favorite color is... elbow.
呃...她最爱的颜色是...王子
I believe Ted was mouthing the word "yellow.
我觉的Ted的嘴型是想说"黄色"
" Which also would have been wrong.
黄色其实也是错的
This game is called "Gilding The Lily.
这个游戏的名字叫"夸夸Lily"
- Nice. - Thank you.
- 不错 - 谢谢
Okay,you've all written down your favorite things about the birthday girl.
好了你们都把最爱Lily的事情 写出来了
And Lilypad,you guess who wrote what.
Lily 你来猜分别谁写的
"Lily makes "everyone in her life,from her friends to her students..."
"Lily让她身边所有的人 从朋友到学生都感觉到她的爱"
Lily's a kindergarten teacher - that's what he means by "students."
Lily是个幼儿园老师 这就是他为什么说学生
"...feel loved. "She makes the best "oatmeal raisin cookies ever,
"她做的燕麦葡萄干饼干最好吃
can recite every line from Goonies...
她能记住的每一句台词"
" Lily saw Goonies in the theater right after her parents separated.
Lily在她父母刚离婚后 去影院看的这个电影
- For a long time after that,she had real trouble trusting people... - Ted!
- 很长时间她都不能相信别人 - Ted!
"And she's the strongest person I've ever met.
"她是我认识的最坚强的人
"I can't imagine my life without her.
不能想象我的生活没有她会如何
I love you,Lily.
我爱你 Lily"
" Aww... Robin!
哦...Robin
- Of course it was me. Come on. - Aww,that's so sweet.
- 当然是我写的 过来 - 太可爱了
Okay,Lily,you try to guess who wrote this.
Lily 你猜谁写的这个
"You seem really nice.
你看上去是个好人
I'm going to guess Amanda?
我猜是Amanda?
No,that w me.
不是 是我写的
And I meant every word.
我这可是发自肺腑
Well,I should get back to that cake.
好吧 我该去看看蛋糕怎么样了
Okay,let me know if you need anything.
好的 有什么需要的就叫我
All right,quick! Let's do the group photo!
好了 快点 我们来拍照!
Everybody gather around the fireplace.
大家都到壁炉这边来
Oh,uh,hang on,I'll,uh,I'll let Amanda know.
哦 等一下 我去叫Amanda
Oh,no,that's okay. She's busy in the kitchen.
不用了 她在厨房里忙了
Let's not bother her. Come on.
我们别去打搅她了 快来
Hey,hang on a second. You...
嘿 等一下
You don't want Amanda in the photo,do you?
你不想让Amanda和我们一起拍照是吧
No,no,it's just,you know,auto-focus,shutter speed,zoom...
不 不 你知道 自动调焦 快门速度 聚焦之类的
Lily,what's going on?
Lily 到底怎么回事
Who wants a party hat?
谁想带生日派对帽?
Hey,look! Look,I'm a bird! Let's all be birds.
快看啊 我是只鸟 我们都来当鸟吧
- Lily,tell me the truth. - No,of course not.
- Lily 跟我说实话 - 我确实不想
I'm not going to let another one of your dumb skanks ruin my precious memories.
我才不想让你带来的又一个惹人嫌的讨厌鬼 破坏了我的珍贵记忆
Lily,what are you talking about?
Lily 你说什么呢?
Ted,you always do this.
Ted 你老是这样
You bring girls that we barely know to all our big group events.
你老是带一些我们不认识的女人 来参加我们的重要聚会
- I do not. - Oh,really?
- 我才没有呢 - 哦 是吗?
Oh,well,let's just take a little walk down Random Skank Lane.
好吧 我们来看看你都有带来过 那些烦人精
Or,or we could just keep on a-strolling down Best Birthday Ever Avenue.
或者我们可以继续这个 我们有史以来最好的生日派对
Do I get a vote? Skank Lane! Skank Lane!
我能表态吗?烦人精!烦人精!
Hey,hey,guys. I've composed a song for the evening.
嘿 嘿 各位 我为今天晚上写了一首歌
Follow along. The chorus goes like this:
大家一起唱 歌词是这样的
Happy,happy Lily day
Lily生日好快乐啊好快乐
- Happy,happy Lily day... - Christmas morning,four years ago.
- Lily生日好快乐啊好快乐 - 圣诞早晨 四年之前
Our first Christmas together,just the five of us.
我们第一个一起过的圣诞节 只有我们五个人
Ooh,Ted,here's another fun little trivia me.
哦 我们来玩这个小游戏
It's called: Name That Bitch.
叫做 这个婊子叫什么
It's,it is Sa... San...
叫 叫 叫 Sa...San
Wrong. You're thinking of Santa,'cause it was Christmas.
错了 你在猜圣诞老人的名字 因为这是圣诞节
Fun fact - each year,my mother has Easter tea with her friend Bunny.
真好笑 每年我妈妈都和她 叫兔兔的朋友过复活节 (复活节兔兔可是主角哦)
Okay,not that fun.
好吧 也没那么好笑
I remember her name. It's Sarah.
我记起她名字来了 叫Sarah
Close. It's Leilani.
差不多了 是叫Leilani
She just had to come to Christmas because you said,"Guys,she might be the one.
你非得叫她来一起过圣诞 因为你说 各位 她可能就是我的真命天女
" And she's not the only "might be the one.
她可不是 唯一的真命天女
" New Year's Eve,2007:
新年夜 2007年
Barney,Lily,Robin,Ted,Marshall and "She's the One" Emily.
Barney,Lily,Robin,Ted,Marshall和 真命天女之Emily
Robin's Uncle Cecil's funeral: Marshall,Lily,Robin,Barney,Ted and...
Robin叔叔Cecil的葬礼 Marshall,Lily,Robin,Barney,Ted和
"this just proves you find the one when you're not looking" Isabel.
街上闭眼随便抓来的真命天女 Isabel
My appenx surgery: Robin,Marshall,Barney,Lily,Ted,and...
我阑尾炎手术 Robin,Marshall,Barney,Lily,Ted和
Well,this one you admitted you were just trying to bang.
哦 这个你至少承认了 你只是想和她上床
Respect.
佩服啊
Oh,hey. Remember this yoga instructor you brought to my birthday last year?
记得我去年生日你带来的这个 瑜伽教练吗
You.
你
Thank you. Thank you. Oh,my - oh,my God.
谢谢 谢谢 哦 天啊 天啊
You guys are not going to believe who just came in.
你们肯定想不到刚是谁进来了
Don't look. Don't look!
别看 别看
Why aren't you looking? !
你们怎么不看啊
It's Slash from Guns N' Roses!
是枪花乐队的Slash!
Okay,okay,group shot. Group shot!
镇定 镇定 拍照 拍照
And we got it.
我们拍到了
We got a picture with Slash on my birthday.
在我生日那天和Slash拍到合影
Awesome,right? Right?
太妙了 是吧? 是吧?
We were there. We know how this ends.
我们当时在 我们知道后来如何
Wrong!
错了!
You know what's funny about this picture? He was grabbing my ass.
你知道这张照片好笑在哪里? 他在捏我屁股
Really? He was grabbing my ass,too.
真的? 他也在捏我屁股
He was grabbing my ass,too - how many hands does that guy have?
他也捏我的屁股了 这家伙到底有几只手啊
No wonder he's such a good guitarist.
怪不得这家伙吉他弹得这么好
Actually,I'm sorry dude,I thought that you were Lily.
我想说抱歉哥们儿 我当时以为你是Lily
Wait a second. Look at these pictures again.
等一下 再看看这些照片
Barney has the same pose in each shot and these are,like,years apart.
Barney这么多年来这么多照片 都是同一个姿势
Ah,yes,about that: I never take a bad picture.
是啊 关于这个 我拍照一直完美的
Never have,never will.
过去是 将来也是
There has to be a bad picture of you.
肯定有张没拍好的
Nope,not one.
没有 一张也没有
What about from elementary school? Everyone has bad pictures from school.
小学的照片呢? 上学的时候谁都有没拍好的照片
Not the Barnacle.
本人从来没有
I always look drop dead,stone cold amazing.
我永远都是惊人地完美
Unlike Marshall,who just looks dead,stoned and cold.
不像Marshall永远是一副死相
He was right,kids.
他说对了 孩子们
Your Uncle Marshall does a lot of things well,
Marshall叔叔很多方面都很好
but he does not take a good picture.
但是他从来没有拍过一张好照片
They're not all bad,okay? Like...
也不是都那么糟糕吧 像
here. Here,look at this one. My eyes are open.
这张 这张 我眼睛睁着呢
- Marshall,no! - Oh,you did put a bow on it.
- Marshall 别! - 哦 你还真打上蝴蝶结了啊
- Chip and dip,Barney? - Sure.
- 吃薯片吗 Barney - 当然
Aha! Got it! A bad picture.
啊哈! 拍到了! 不完美照片
Is it though?
果真如此?
No! Wait! You were eating a chip!
不会吧 等一下 你在吃薯片!
Where's the chip?
薯片去哪里了?
It is physically impossible for me to take a bad picture.
对我来说拍不好照片是不可能的
I don't know why. Ask God.
我不知道为什么 问上帝吧
Look,Lily,I'm sorry about Amanda.
听着 Lily 关于Amanda我很抱歉
I'm just going to say it. You are being a birthday brat.
但是我还是要说 你纯粹是在耍小孩子脾气
You're all bent out of shape just 'cause you think I ruined a couple pictures.
你们都这么不高兴 就因为我破坏了几张照片?
Oh,Ted. These girls have ruined so many events,
哦 Ted 这些女孩破坏了好多聚会
or are you forgetting Paris?
或者你忘了巴黎的事情了?
What happened in Paris?
巴黎发生什么事情了?
It was junior year and I was studying abroad in Paris,
大学三年级 我到巴黎去学习
and I hadn't seen Marshall for two months.
我和Marshall两个月没见面了
Two months. And I had just started having sex.
两个月啊! 我们才刚开始有性生活
I wasn't ready to stop for two months.
我根本没准备好要中断两个月
And Marshall was coming to visit over spring break.
Marshall打算春假时来看我
And at the last minute,Ted decided to come
最后时刻 Ted决定跟来
with the girl he had just gotten back together with,Karen.
还带着一个刚复合的女友 Karen
Karen.
Karen
I am so excited you're here.
你能来我太兴奋了
I'm so excited to go to Paris.
一起去巴黎我太兴奋了
I'm so excited to have sex again.
能重新体验性生活我太兴奋了
But just before the plane took off...
就在飞机起飞前一刻
Wait,I want to tell you something.
等一下 我有事情要告诉你
Really? 'Cause I think I want to tell you the same thing.
真的? 因为我想告诉你同样的话
Is your thing,I had sex with my philosophy professor last night?
你要说的是  我昨天晚上和哲学教授上床了?
'Cause that's my thing.
我要说的就是这个
And thus began the longest seven and a half hours of Marshall's life.
就此 Marshall人生中最漫长的 7个半小时开始了
When I picked them up at the airport...
我去机场接他们的时候...
Ted broke up with me.
Ted和我分手了
I need to sleep in your room this week.
这个礼拜我要跟你睡一起
Marshall can bunk with Ted.
Marshall能和Ted挤挤
Two months! My balls were bleu! Bleu!
两个月! 我的蛋蛋都憋蓝了! 蓝了! (法语)
This will come as no shock,but the rest of the trip was terrible.
这还不算什么 但是之后的旅行 糟糕透顶
And all I wanted was a romantic kiss picture
我只想在艾菲尔塔前拍一张
in front of the Eiffel Tower,which I actually did get.
浪漫的亲吻照片 我还真的拍到叻
It just happened to be between Karen and Francois,
结果是Karen和Francois
our waiter from the day before.
就是前一天的服务生
Wow,that's just awful.
太糟糕了
Just... Ugh! Just-Just...
太... 嗯! 太... 太...
- Oopsies! Hey. I dropped my phone. You mind picking it up for me? - Oh,sure.
- 哎呀! 我的相机掉了 能帮我捡一下吗? - 当然
Smile,you son of a bitch! Got it!
笑一个 你个混蛋! 拍到了!
Did you,though?
果真如此?
Wait. How do you do that?! You weren't even standing up!
等等 你怎么做到的?! 你根本没站起来!
The camera loves me,Robin.
照相机爱我 Robin
More than loves me. The camera lusts after me.
不只是爱我 照相机对我如饥似渴
The camera wants to put on some nice lingerie,
照相机想穿上性感内衣
pop in an Al Green CD,dim the lights and do all the work
放Al Green CD里的歌 调节好弱光 搞定所有的事
while I just lie there with my eyes closed.
而我只要闭着眼睛躺着就好了
Look,I'm sorry about Paris and all the ruined group shots,
巴黎那次 还有所有搞残的集体照 我很抱歉
but when you're single,you got to hope that each next new girl is the one.
但单身的时候 每一次你总要抱着 下个姑娘肯定能成的希望
- I mean,Erin. - Emily.
- 你看Erin - Emily
- Irene. - Or Isabel.
- Irene - Isabel
- And Sarah. - It's Leilani. What is wrong with you?
- 还有Sarah. - 是Leilani 你哪根筋搭错了?
At the time,yes,I thought each of these girls could be the one,
那个时候 我真的觉得 她们都有可能成
but I got to stay hopeful.
我总得怀揣希望
I mean,what's the alternative?
不然还能怎么着?
Here's the alternative. How about no more random skanks at my birthday!
就这样 你别再随随便便带个讨厌鬼 来参加我的生日派对!
Hey,sweetie!
亲爱的!
Hi. Uh,do you guys have a cooling rack?
你们有冷却架吗?
Oh,drawer under the oven. Can't wait. You're just the best!
在烤箱下面的抽屉里 快去吧 你最棒了!
Ted,I'm sorry. I gonna have to agree with Lily on this.
Ted 很抱歉在这点上 我不得不同意Lily
I mean,these kind of events are hard for a new person.
新朋友参加这些聚会太勉强
That's why I didn't bring Don tonight.
这就是为什么今晚我不带Don过来
I mean,when I lived in Japan,this guy,for our third date,
我住在日本的时候 这个男人 在第三次约会的时候
brought me to his brother's wedding.
带我参加他哥哥的婚礼
Now,I- a total stranger-
现在 我...一个彻头彻尾的陌生人
am in that Japanese couple's wedding picture for all eternity.
永远留在那对日本夫妇的结婚照里了
Name***
那个婊子叫什么!
Yeah,Ted,I think you should listen to Robin.
对 Ted 我觉得你应该听Robin的
Right,right,'cause... 'cause Robin's your best friend.
是啊是啊 因为... 因为 Robin是你最好的朋友
- Exactly. - Your best friend in the whole world.
- 当然 - 全世界最好的朋友
- Absolutely. - Careful,Lily. It's a trap.
- 那是 - 当心 Lily 是陷阱
And before she was your best friend,what was she?
在她成为你最好的朋友之前 是什么?
Oh,that's right. One of my random skanks.
哦 对了 是我随便带来的讨厌鬼之一
Okay,yes,Ted. This particular skank...
好了 没错 Ted 这位特殊的讨厌鬼...
... happened to work out,but she's the skanky exception,not the skanky rule.
碰巧成了 但是她是讨厌鬼中的例外 不是不是讨厌鬼中的惯例...
Okay,I'm crying a little bit.
行了 我要哭了
Okay. Hey,guys,that about wraps up this whole skank conversation.
伙计们 不要继续这个讨厌鬼的话题了
Let's get back to the birthday song!
我们来唱生日歌吧!
Okay,um,Barney,your part goes like this.
好 Barney 你这样唱
She's cute She's cute.
她很可爱 她很可爱 她很可爱
Lily,I bring girls to these events
Lily 我带这些姑娘来参加聚会
because you guys are important to me. You're my family.
因为你们对我很重要 是我的家人
And,oh,hey,Robin.
Robin 你 嗨 Robin
Hey,Robin,Robin,your part goes like this.
Robin Robin 你这样唱
And nice and nice And also nice!
还很善良 还很善良 还很善良!
Yes. We're a family.
是的 我们是家人
So why can't these events ever just be us?
为什么这些聚会不可以只有我们?
Like the time we celebrated Marshall passing the bar exam.
就像Marshall通过律师考试那次
Hey. Hey,guys.
嘿 伙计们
This is the disgusting,smelly hippie I'm dating.
这就是那个我在交往的 讨厌的 臭臭的小妞
I did not say that!
我没那样说!
Well,you might as well have.
你还不如这样说
Hey,guys. This is Strawberry.
嘿 伙计们 这是草莓
Um,should we order more food?
我们还要再点一些吗?
Oh,no. Uh,Strawberry's not eating.
不用 草莓不吃
I'm a vegetarian.
我是吃素的
Okay. Well,let's all raise a glass.
好 让我们举杯
For the last three years,Marshall has been working so hard,
过去的三年 Marshall非常努力
and I am so proud of you.
我为你骄傲
Meat is murder! Murder!
吃肉的都是凶手! 凶手!
Okay,I admit it. Strawberry was a mistake.
我承认草莓是个错误
But how could I have known that going in?
但我怎么可能知道会有这种事?
Her name was Strawberry.
因为她叫草莓
Look,if it's such a big deal,Amanda doesn't have to be in the group photo.
听着 如果真的这么介意 Amanda 不一定要一起拍集体照
But I promise she's not gonna ruin your birthday.
但我保证她不会毁了你的生日
Just-Just give her a chance.
只要... 只要给她一次机会
See,look,guys. We're all friends again!
看 伙计们 我们又和好了!
Now let's work on those harmonies.
现在我们要排一下和声
Happy happy Lily day!
Lily生日真快乐真快乐!
Happy happy Lily day...
Lily生日真快乐真快乐!...
All done.
做好了
I hope you like it.
希望你能喜欢
"Happy 42nd birthday,Lori.
"42岁生日快乐 Lori"
" Kids,you know how I've told you about Lily's "you're dead to me" look-
孩子们 我有没有跟你们说过 Lily这副"你死定了"的表情"
that expression she gets just before she explodes in white-hot rage?
是她怒发冲冠之前的征兆吗?
Well,this wasn't it.
这个并不是
But this was Marshall's.
但是Marshall这个是
"42nd"?
"42岁"?
Does this hot piece of ass look 42 to you?
你看这个性感小妞像42岁吗?
Or! Or does she look like her name is Lori? !
还是! 还是她看起来就得叫Lori?!
No,Marshall,it's okay.
算了 Marshall 没关系
No,Lily,it's not okay. Ted,get this stranger out of my house!
不行 Lily 有关系 Ted 让这个陌生人从我家出去!
I am so sorry.
我很抱歉
Out!
出去!
Happy,happy Lily day Happy,happy Lily day.
Lily生日真快乐哟 Lily生日真快乐哟 (小Barney 我爱你啊 你太cute了)
Well... Amanda refused to come back.
... Amanda不肯回来
She thinks you guys hate her.
她觉得你们讨厌她
Marshall,you have to go apologize.
Marshall 你得去道歉
You ruin Lily's birthday and you want me to apologize?
你把Lily的生日搞砸了 要我道歉?
If anything,you should apologize to me.
说起来 你应该跟我道歉
What are you talking about?
你说什么?
Ted,you bring girls to these intimate events
Ted 你把姑娘带来参加 密友的聚会
and it makes them think that things are really serious.
让她们觉得你很认真
And then when you break up with them,you know who they turn to? Me.
然后你跟她们分手 你知道她们找上谁吗? 找上我
I've been your girlfriend cleanup crew for yea.
我当了你多少年女友抚慰专员
February,2005.
2005年 2月
I had just come back from a marathon study session at the law library.
我在法律图书馆漫长的课 刚结束回来
Hey. Hey,Natalie,where's,uh,where's Ted?
嘿 Natalie Ted在哪儿?
We broke up... again!
我们... 又分手了!
Won't you sit with me for a little while? Just sit?
你能不能坐这儿陪我一会? 坐着就好?
Man,you know what? I've been up for,like,36 hours.
大小姐 你要知道 我大概有 36个小时没睡过了
Just for a few minutes.
就几分钟
And at first,I was completely sympathetic.
一开始 我很有同情心
But damn it,Ted,over the years,you made me cynical.
不过Ted 他妈的搞了这么多年 你把我逼得铁石心肠了
You know what? I'm going to go get us some Rocky Road,
我去搞点石板街蛋糕过来
and we're just going to sit here and talk it out until it makes sense.
我们就坐在这儿 陪聊到你想通为止
I just thought we had something so special,you know?
我以为我们有特别之处 你知道吗?
Me,too. Yeah.
我理解 嗯
But,you know,life goes on,sweetheart.
但是 你知道 生活还得继续  亲爱的
I don't know how I'm going to put my life back together after this.
我不知道分了手我要怎么过下去
Oh,shut up.
哦 闭嘴
Well,I'm sorry my search for true love
很抱歉因为我寻找真爱之旅
has been such an inconvenience to you guys.
给你们添了这么多麻烦
You know what? Maybe your precious pictures
要知道 说不定你那些珍贵的照片
would look a lot better if I wasn't in them.
少了我会更好
They'd look a lot better if Marshall weren't in them.
如果少了Marshall会更好
Cheap shot,bro. Cheap shot.
贱招儿 贱招儿
You know what these pictures are,Lily?
你知道这些照片是什么吗 Lily?
They're a big,fat lie. They're posed. They're touched up.
是彻彻底底的谎言 都是做出来的 都做过手脚
They're what you want our life to be,not what it is.
是你期望中的生活 而不是真实的情况
- That's not true! - Oh,yeah?
- 乱讲! - 是吗?
Okay. Look at this one. Halloween,two years ago.
看这张 两年前万圣节前夜
You and Marshall got in a huge fight
你和Marshall大吵一架
because you didn't want to dress up as penguins.
因为你不想穿成企鹅
No,no-no,it's not just that she didn't want to.
不是 不是 不是她不想穿
It's that she called penguins "lame. " Penguins.
是她觉得企鹅是很傻的 企鹅
And yet,here you are,smiling like nothing's wrong - completely phony.
但是你还笑得像什么事都没有一样 太假了
Robin's birthday,three years ago.
三年前 Robin生日
Robin had a cold and you made her change
Robin感冒了 你逼她把睡衣换了
out of her pajama's for the picture.
拍照片
And then you pinched my cheeks really hard to get some color in them.
你还使劲捏我的脸 搞点血色出来
Yeah,but you look pretty.
是的 但是看上去美美的
And then,we all ate chocolate cake in my bed.
后来大家在我的床上吃巧克力蛋糕
- Actually,that was a really nice night. - Yeah,it was.
- 其实那天晚上很开心 - 嗯 确实
Yeah,I guess it was.
是啊 是的 (友谊万岁)
Hey,look at this one.
看这张
This is the first picture the three of us ever took together.
这是我们三个一起拍的第一张照片
That's right. It was.
对哦 是的耶
Yeah,you remember how it happened?
嗯 你记得当时什么情况吗?
Okay,ready?
好 准备好了吗?
Wait,wait,wait. What pose should we do? Buddy cop picture?
等等 等等 我们拗什么造型? 警探拍档剧照?
Oh,no,no-no! What about,um,'80s sitcom about two roommates who never agree on anything?
不 不要 不要! 80年代拍那个两个 总是对着干的室友的肥皂剧呢?
Nice. Okay,one,two...
不错 好 一 二...
Hi,Marshall. Ready for the movie?
嗨 Marshall 准备好去看电影了吗?
Um,yeah. Just a second though,okay? We're about to make history.
去啊 就等一会儿 好吗? 我们要记录历史性的一刻
We're about to take our first ever roommate picture.
我们要拍第一张室友合照
Yeah. Hey,why don't you get in the picture,too?
对 要不你也一起来拍吧?
- Really? - Yeah.
- 真的? - 真的
What are you doing,Ted? What if we break up?
你干什么 Ted? 要是我们分手了怎么办?
What if you don't?
要是不分手呢?
Come on. Come on.
来吧 来吧
I forgot all about that.
我都快忘了
Marshall and I had just been dating a few weeks
Marshall和我刚交往几个星期
and you invited me into the picture.
你请我一起拍照片
I liked you.
我喜欢你嘛
- We have to get Amanda back. - Really?
- 我们得叫Amanda回来 - 真的?
Ted,you believed in me. It's my turn to believe in you.
Ted 你相信我 这次轮到我相信你了
For all I know,she's the one.
我知道她一定能成
Thanks,Lil.
谢谢 Lily
I think Lori's age has made her very wise.
我觉得Lori的年纪让她长不少脑子
They say your forties are when you really get to know yourself.
他们说40岁的时候 你才能真正了解自己
So,your Aunt Lily called Amanda.
所以Lily阿姨把Amanda叫回来
All right,people,gather around. Let's make a memory.
好了 大家凑紧点 我们留个念
Okay,Marshall - Marshall,try this.
Marshall Marshall 试试看这招
Keep your eyes closed until the last second,
闭上眼睛 一直到最后一秒
- and when I say so,open them. - Okay.
- 我说睁开 你再睁开 - 好
Hey,Barney,is that a hole in your suit jacket?
Barney 你的外套上是不是有个洞?
What? Where?
什么? 哪儿?
Now,Marshall!
就现在 Marshall!
Damn it!
该死!
Ted,name that bitch.
Ted 这婊子叫什么
Birth... a? Bertha?
生...? Bertha?
No,it was my birthday.
不对 你是想说生日
Your brain makes associations in a very obvious way.
你脑子的联想模式太简单了
All right,people. Gather around. Let's make a memory.
好了 大家凑一起 我们留个念
Hey,Robin,what's in this dip you made? 'Cause it tastes like...
那个 Robin 你在蘸酱里放了什么? 我尝出...
cilantro.
芫荽叶的味道
And you know that cilantro makes me...
你知道芫荽叶会让我...
Yes!
太好了!
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=- Proudly Presents
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=- 感谢收看